→ ESA和中国航天员一起参与训练
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/Ag6jpXIUUaQ
原视频发布日期：20170922
原作者名：European Space Agency, ESA
这是第一次 欧空局在中国组织进行航天员培训活动
For the first time ever, ESA has been conducting astronaut training activities in China.
Matthias Maurer和Samantha Cristoforetti最近和7名中国航天员在一起
Matthias Maurer and Samantha Cristoforetti recently joined 7 Chinese astronauts -
或者说太空人 进行了9天的海上生存培训课程 在中国滨海城市烟台市外
or Taikonauts - for a nine day sea survival training session off China's coastal city of Yantai.
我们基本上是在为异常着陆而进行培训
We are basically practising what would happen if there was an off-nominal landing,
we wouldn't land on the ground but we would actually land in the water,
我们不会在陆地上着陆 而是在海里溅落
欧空局宇航员
and we would have to survive independently for some time and using the rescue boats,
我们将不得不独立生存一段时间 并使用急救艇
使用急救设备 并且自主地离开返回舱
the rescue equipment and exiting of course the re-entry capsule autonomously.
穿着压力服
Wearing pressure suits,
宇航员进入了神舟飞船的实体模型 之后被释放到海里
the astronauts entered a mock-up Shenzhou capsule that was then released into the sea.
Samantha和Matthias分别和另外两个中国航天员组队
Samantha and Matthias were each teamed with two Taikonauts –
这种配置更接近于实际情况
who between them have considerable spaceflight experience.
在穿上绝缘且有浮力的服装后
After donning insulation and buoyancy suits,
他们演练了有船和直升机情况下的急救程序
they practised rescue procedures with both a ship and a helicopter.
太空任务可能是充满意外的 而类似这样的培训课程
Space missions can be unpredictable – and training exercises such as these
可以确保宇航员应对各种情况
ensure that astronauts are prepared for every eventuality.
The training experience so far is great,
到目前为止 培训给我的体验很棒
the Chinese are really well-prepared – it's high-level equipment, we get helicopter airlifting,
中国人准备真的很周全 装备很高级 我们进行了直升机空运
有个巨大的使用在公海上的海上生存救援船
we have a huge sea-survival rescue ship which is usually employed on the high seas,
所以到目前为止 是很好的装备和体验
so very good equipment and a very good experience so far.
和Samantha还有Matthias一起在中国的还有一个欧空局的飞行外科医生
Accompanying Samantha and Matthias in China were an ESA flight surgeon
以及一个培训专家 了解了文化的细微差异
and a training specialist – who gained insights into the different cultural nuances and approaches.
During this training I've had the opportunity to work very closely with our Chinese medical colleagues,
在这个培训中 我有机会与中国的医疗同事们密切合作
欧空局飞行外科医生
and I'm very, very impressed about how they have combined their traditional Chinese medicine,
关于他们如何现代化传统中国医药 我对此非常印象深刻
这种医药有着上千年的历史
which has thousands of years of history,
但是他们会把中医与世界上最先进的医药知识结合在一起
with the most advanced medical knowledge that we can find now in the world.
这里的培训组织得很好
Training here is very, very well organised.
So we have different ways of approaching training, which is inherited from the ISS programme,
我们有着不同的培训方法 继承自国际空间站的项目
欧空局培训专家
但实际上这之间的差异并不大
but actually they are not that far away,
这就意味着我们在培训组织中能够找到共同语言
so it means that we find common words and common understanding in the way they also organise training,
所以 对我们来说 这是一个非常好的信号 可以和中国人进一步合作
so for us it's a very good sign for further co-operation with the Chinese.
这次培训不是两家机构的第一次合作了
This training exercise wasn't the first collaboration between the two space agencies.
2016年7月 中国航天员叶光富参加了欧空局在撒丁岛的洞穴课程
In July 2016, Chinese astronaut Ye Guangfu joined ESA's caving course in Sardinia
在多元文化团队的氛围中 体验极端环境
to experience an extreme environment as part of a multicultural crew.
这两项活动都源自于2015年的协议
Both activities stem from the 2015 agreement to boost collaboration
来加速欧空局和中国载人航天办公室的合作
between ESA and the China Manned Space Agency -
最终目标是在2022年让欧洲航天员进入中国空间站
with the ultimate goal of flying European astronauts onboard the Chinese space station from 2022.
This joint training we are doing here is a first step in a co-operation
我们在这儿做的这个合作培训是合作的第一步
that we all hope will lead one day in the early 2020s to a European astronaut
我们都希望有朝一日 在2020年代初 让一个欧洲航天员
能和中国航天员去未来的中国空间站
flying with the Taikonauts to the future Chinese space station,
所以当然了 如果我有这样的机会 我会很激动
so of course I would be thrilled if I had that opportunity.
由中国航天员中心组织
Organised by the Astronaut Centre of China
以及交通运输部北海救助局合作
in co-operation with the Ministry of Transport's Beihai Rescue Bureau,
本次培训班是实现长期合作的一个重要步骤
this training session has been an important step towards long-term collaboration.
其他培训机会 联合活动正在酝酿中
Other training opportunities and joint activities are in the pipeline –
目的是帮助欧空局和中国载人航天办公室促进互相的了解
with the aim of helping ESA and the China Manned Space Agency to get to know one another better.